原创翻译:shhaclm@CHDBits
校订翻译:北卧鱼
伊朗沙漠地带
德黑兰东南200英里
1980年4月25日上午4点整
[man] Let's go, first class!Get on there!
快走，第一队到这里来！
Move it! Move it! Move it!
快！快！快！
[man] Move it! Sergeant,get your men on there! Let's go!
快点，军士，叫你的人快点上飞机
Is that Peterson's helicopter?
那是彼德的直升机吗？
He was in that damn chopper that blew up.
对，彼德还在飞机上呢
McCoy! McCoy, get back here!
麦考！麦考！快回来
Where the hell are you going? We're pullin' out.
你要去哪儿？飞机要起飞了！
Captain McCoy!
麦考上尉！
- Bobby, where's Pete?
- 彼德在哪儿？
- Still in the damn chopper.
- 被困在飞机上了
The flames are too high.We tried, but he can't be reached.
火势太猛，我们冲不进去
Captain, don't go in there! The fuel bladders are about to blow!
队长，别去了，燃料箱随时会爆炸的
Pete! Pete!
彼德！彼德！
Pete, where are you?
彼德，你在哪儿？
[Pete] Get the hell out of here, man! The thing's gonna blow!
你别过来，这儿危险！会爆炸！
Scott?
快走吧，麦考
God damn it, get out of here! This god damn thing's gonna blow!
快走吧！这儿要爆炸了！
Hang on.
你别泄气
[Pete] Get out!
快走！
Hang on, Pete.
别泄气，彼德
Get out of here!
你快走！
Oh, my God! My leg's gone!
啊，上帝！我的腿不行了
Come on!
过来
[Pete] Get outta here, Captain!
快走吧，队长
Listen, Pete. When I raise up the Jeep, move your leg.
听着，彼德，我抬起吉普时你缩腿
Ready?
明白吗？
Move it!
用力！
- Move your leg! Pete, move it!
挪动你的腿！彼德，用力！
- Ah！
啊!
Ah!
啊！
Lean on me.
靠着我
Move, move. Get 'em up here.Come on, move.
快，快拉他们上去
All right, take it up. Let's go.
好，关上门，我们走
Colonel, Scott and Pete are still back there.
上校，麦考和彼德还在后面呢
They're two men. I got a whole squadron to think about. Come on. Get it up!
他们只有两个人，我要为大家负责．快，起飞！
Hey, there they are.
晦！他们来了！
Come on, Scott! Come on!
快，麦考！快点
- Take it down. Take it down!
快点！快点
- You're gonna make it!
你真行
- Come on, man!
就等你们了！
- [man] Move those on down. Right away!
快点
- Get that ammo secured.
把弹药挪到一边去
- Come on, man.
帮他们一把，快！
Come on! All right, we've got him.
干得好，我们抓住他们了
Come on. Here we go. Let's go.
快，我们进去
Come on. Make a move. Go.
快，让一下
- Come on. Close the door.
快，关舱门！
- Give him some room.
给他一些地方
- All right.
好了，
- Let's go.
起飞
Why in the hell wouldn't they listen, Nick?
尼克，你为什么不听指挥？
We told 'em it's too dangerous to launch this operation at night.
我早就说过晚上行动太危险了
They thought their plan was better.
他们总是认为他们的计划做得好
I spent five years in Vietnam watching them doing the planning...
我去越南那五年也是按照他们的计划干的…
...and us the dying.
可结果就是我们的死亡
Well...
好了…
...I'm resigning when I get back.
我回去后决定不干了
[TV] We interrupt this program to bring you the following special news bulletin.
插播一条特别公告
We have just received word that an hour ago,
一条来自一小时前的消息
an attempt to rescue the American hostages held in Teheran
一次尝试解救困在德黑兰的美国人质
ended in disaster for the Army's top-secret antiterrorist special forces.
以美军顶级特别反恐部队的失败告终
Eight members of the special unit have been killed and 13 wounded
8名队员丧生，13名受伤
according to first count.
根据初次统计
No further information as to the cause of this disaster or its outcome
尚无更多信息显示会导致此次救援失败
is available at this time.
目前能够提供
雅典
1985年7月19日星期五上午7:45
[woman on PA] American Travelways flight 282 from Cairo has just landed.
从开罗飞来的美航282号航班已经降落了
Passengers taking this flight to New York via Rome
乘坐本次飞抵纽约途径罗马航班的旅客
should proceed to gate 11.
请到11号登机门
[PA] Flight 22 now arriving at gate five.
22号航班已于5号登机门候机
- Attention please, flight 22...
一请注意，22号航班…
- I have a bad leg.
一我的腿不好
I thought you would like to know
我想你一定乐于知道…
we're celebrating our silver wedding anniversary.
我们正在庆祝我们的银婚纪念日
- Congratulations.
祝贺你们
- Thank you.
谢谢
Don't congratulate us. We'd have gotten divorced years ago,
别祝贺我们．我们几年前就离婚了
but either one of us wanted custody of our kids.
但我们两个都想得到子女的监护权
- Please don't listen to him.
别听他瞎说
- Ha!Ha!
哈哈
If it was up to him,he would spoil 'em rotten.
如果交给他，他一定会把他们教坏
- Know what? I'm going shopping.
我们去逛逛商店怎样？
- Good idea.
好主意
- I'm gonna see what my daughter's...
我正想去给女儿买点…
- You wanna go to the duty-free?
你想去免税店吗？
Let's go. Watch the things, honey.
走吧．亲爱的，看好行李
- Harry Goldman. Philadelphia.
我叫哈利·戈德曼，菲勒多菲亚人
- Ben Kaplan. New York.
本·卡普兰，纽约人
Deborah, let her have the doll she wants. She's a baby.
狄波拉，你就给她买个娃娃吧，她还小呐．
Mama, she's not a baby, and you're spoiling her.
妈，她不小了，你太宠她了
I'm not spoiling her. I didn't do such a bad job with you.
我没有宠她，我也从没对你恶过
You know, Harry wanted to buy me a new ring for our anniversary.
哈利本来想给我买个纪念戒指
I said no.
我说不要
He got me this ring in Jerusalem on our honeymoon.
他就给我买了这个戒子，是在耶鲁撒冷度蜜月时买的
Really? Oh, it's lovely. What does it say?
是吗？真漂亮！这上面写的什么？
One minute. I'll show you.Here, take it.
等会，我脱下来给你看看，拿着
It says... [speaks Hebrew]
这上面写着…［希伯来语]
Ah, that's... That's Hebrew. I know that.
噢，是希伯来文，我知道了
It's from the Song of Songs.
那是一首老歌
"Me to my lover, my lover to me."
你爱着我，我爱着你
You're Jewish, huh?
你是犹太人？
- No, I'm Chinese.
不，我是中国人
- Of course.
当然
What's the problem?
有什么事吗？
There's no problem, Miss.We thought you had a water leak.
没事，小姐，听说厕所漏水了
Can we start boarding now?
可以让乘客登机了吗？
Sure. Better check that with your flight engineer.
可以，最好和机师一起检查一下
Have a nice flight.
一路顺风
I'm sorry, sir, this flight is full.
对不起，这次航班已经满客了
Please check the ticket counter for the next available flight.
请到售票柜台去查询下一班航班
No, I must be on this flight.
不，我必须搭乘这班航班
I'm sorry. You have a stand-by ticket.
对不起，这是你的候补机票
We're full, sir. Please move aside.
这航班已经满了，请你到边上去
You see in your book. Maybe there is space.
你再去查一查嘛，也许还有空位的
Sir, you can't go on board this flight.
你没法乘坐这次航班了，先生
You can...You see if there is a place for me.
你能不能再查一查，看还有没有空位
They told me there is a place.
他们说还有空座的
- Move aside, please.
请让开
- No, you move aside!
不行，你让开！
They told me I got a ticket!They told me there is a place for me!
他们告诉我可以买票，并说会有空位的
- Send security immediately.
请立刻派保安人员过来
Calm down. Show me your ticket.
请冷静，让我看下你的机票
Here. Here. You see?
在这儿呢，看吧
[man] Stand-by ticket...
候补机票…
Where's my back brace?
我的靠垫在哪儿？
Robert has your back brace, Ma.
在罗伯特那儿，妈妈
Thank you.
谢谢
[over PA] Good morning,ladies and gentlemen.
女士们，先生们，早上好
This is your captain speaking.
我是本次航班机长
My name is Roger Campbell.
罗杰·坎贝尔
On behalf of American Travelways,
我代表美国航空公司
I'd like to welcome you aboard a continuation of flight 282 to Rome,
欢迎你们搭乘282航班经由罗马
then onward to New York. Our flight time to Rome will be 55 minutes.
然后飞往纽约．我们的飞机飞到罗马需要55分钟
- Don't be scared to take off.
别紧张，放松点
- Honey, I can't do this.
亲爱的，我绑不上
- Could you pull this for me?
你能不能帮我绑一下？
- Yes.
好的
Don't kill me, just pull.
别憋死我，拉上就行了
-Take a deep breath.
做下深呼吸
-I won't kill you.
放松点
- Stop it.
去你的
- I'm kidding.
我开个玩笑
Are you all right, Sister?
你哪儿不舒服，女士？
- Could I have a glass of water, please?
能给我倒杯水吗？
- Sure.
好的
She's afraid of flying.
她害怕坐飞机
Sister wants to get to heaven.
她总是祈祷能进天堂
She just doesn't want to fly to get there.
但她可不想坐飞机去那里
[chuckles] I'll get you some.
我去给你倒水
Excuse me. You're from Chicago, no?
请问，你是不是芝加哥来的？
Yes. Yes, we are. How did you know?
是的，你是怎么知道的？
I am from Chicago myself.
我自己也是芝加哥人
I must have seen you somewhere in Chicago.
我肯定在芝加哥什么地方见过你们
You don't sound like Chicago.
你的口音不像芝加哥的
Actually, I've only been in Chicago four years.
实际上我才在芝加哥呆了4年
- You're Polish?
你是波兰人？
- Russian.
我是俄罗斯人
Do you know the orthodox church by Lincoln Park? Father Duchinsky.
你知道林肯公园旁边的东正教教堂吗？里面有个神父叫达钦斯基
I go to hear his sermon every Sunday.
我每个星期天都去听他布道
- Are you going back home?
准备回家是吗？
- My first vacation since Russia.
我自离开俄罗斯后这是第一次度假
- Enjoyed yourself?
玩得开心吗？
- I feel like I am reborn.
我觉得就像获得了重生
America has been good to us.
对我来说美国是最合适的地方
感谢上帝
Oh, shit.
靠
- Daddy, look.
爸爸你看！
- Let me sleep.
别吵我
This is a hijack! Heads down! Heads down!
劫机了！都给我趴下！趴下！
Everybody down! This is a hand grenade! We will blow the plane!
大家都趴下！我有手雷！我会炸毁飞机
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
- Get your heads down!
趴下！
- What are you doing?
你要干什么？
- Get down, everybody!
每个人都趴下！
- Put your heads down!
脸朝下！
- Heads down!
趴下！
- This is a hijack!
这是劫机！
This is a hand grenade!
这是手雷！
We will blow the plane if you do not do exactly as we say!
如果你们不照我说的做，我们就炸掉飞机
Put your hands on your head!
手抱住头！
Oh, my God!
噢，上帝！
No!
不！
Robert, are you all right?
罗伯特，你没事吧？
We are prepared to die. Do not provoke me.
我们都不怕死，别逼我们
You want to die, you die someplace else.
你想死就找个地方，别死在这儿
[shushing] Mister... Don't. Don't.
先生，别…别…
Don't. Don't.
别开枪，别开枪
- Cockpit. Come.
到驾驶舱去…
- We will cooperate.
我们好好商量
- Open...
开门…
- Calm down. We'll cooperate, man.
冷静，先生，我们好商量
- We'll do anything you want.
我们会满足你们的要求的
- Open the cockpit. Open the cockpit.
打开驾驶舱，打开驾驶舱
Open this door.
开门
Jim, it's me. Open.
吉姆，是我，请开门
Open, Jim.
请开门，吉姆
[Jim] Is everything OK?
没什么事吧？
Everything is all right. Open, please.
一切正常，请开门
Open this door or I will blow the plane!
快开门！要不我就炸了这架飞机！
Jim, you have to open!
杰姆，你必须开门！
Pick it up.
捡起来
Move. Sit down.
你走吧．坐下，都坐下
I am taking over this airplane. You will cooperate.
现在我接管这架飞机，你们要合作
We'll take you anywhere you wanna go, buddy.
你们要去哪儿我们送你们去，伙计
Now, why don't you put that pin back into that hand grenade?
不过现在请你把保险针放回手雷上去好吗？
Put it.
放回去
Easy, Jim.
别紧张，吉姆
I am prepared to die. I am Abdul Rafai.
我已经准备一死，我叫阿布杜尔·拉菲
I am a commander in the New World Revolution.
领导着一个叫新世界的革命组织
You will take orders from me and from no one but me,
你们要服从我的命令，要是谁敢反抗
or I will blow this airplane.Do you hear me?
我就会炸掉这架飞机，听明白了吗？
Loud and clear.
听明白了
Now, you fly to Beirut.
现在飞往贝鲁特
- Where?
哪儿？
- Beirut. Fly to Beirut.
贝鲁特，飞往贝鲁特
Beirut.
贝鲁特
Roger.
明白
What are you doing? Take your hand away.
你这是干什么？把手拿开
That's normal operating procedure.
这是标准的操作程序
不好，飞机被劫持了，马上联系美国大使馆
Dave, contact Athens departure control.
戴维，和雅典机场控制室联系
No!
不！
You will fly by map. I know flying. You will fly by map.
你就按照地图飞，我懂飞行，你按地图飞
I don't think we have enough fuel, Captain.
我担心燃料不够，机长
Then you will fly until your fuel runs out, Captain.
那你就飞到燃料用完再说，机长
That is all.
明白了吗？
[man over radio] American Embassy? This is the Athens airport tower.
美国大使馆，这里是雅典航空塔台
Get me the communications officer. It's urgent.
请接联络官，有紧急情况
[man 2] This is the deputy chief officer of the American Embassy in Athens.
我是美国驻雅典使馆副长官
Get me the State Department Operations Center.
请接国务院行动中心
This is an emergency. We need immediate access.
紧急情况，需要马上联络
[man 3] I'm reporting a hijack.
报告一次劫机情况
The incident occurred five minutes ago aboard American Travelways flight 282,
美国航空公司282航班5分钟前被劫持
华盛顿特区
7月9日星期五凌晨2:10
en route from Athens via Rome to New York.
航线从雅典起飞途经罗马飞往纽约
We have no more information at present as to the status of the situation.
目前尚无更多相关信息
五角大楼
7月19日星期五凌晨2:15
[man 4] This is the Secretary of State.
我是美国国务卿
I have a priority flash for the president.
我有紧急情况向总统先生汇报
[man 5] Yes, Mr. Secretary.I'll put the president on the line.
国务卿，马上为您接总统先生
Evening.
晚上好！
As you know, we have a major crisis in the Middle East.
中东发生的危机诸位都知道了
The president has decided
总统已经决定
to send the Delta Force into the area immediately.
马上派三角洲部队去那个地区
Now, what we have to do is work out an emergency rescue operation.
现在迫切需要制订一个详细的营救计划
Get me Nick Alexander at Bragg.
立刻通知在布拉格堡的尼克·亚历山大
布拉格堡
北卡罗来纳7月19日星期五凌晨2 : 20
Has anybody ever told you you've got beautiful legs?
每人说你长了两条美腿吗？
Ah, come on, Nick. You can't see 'em from over there.
得了，尼克，你根本就没看清我的腿
Well, I got a good imagination. I, uh, was just tryin' to be nice.
嗯，我这个人想象力特别丰富，我只是想证实一下
Anyone ever accuse you of being a gentleman, Nick?
有没有听人说过你绅士风度十足，尼克
- Not lately.
我没听说过
Grab me the phone,would you, sweetheart?
能把电话给我用下吗，宝贝？
Alexander here.
亚历山大
Put Delta Force on a phase three alert.ATW Flight 282 was just hijacked.
命令特种部队集合，美航282客机被劫
Get Saber Squadron and fly to the Middle East.
你们立刻搭乘军机飞往中东
- Lebanon?
去黎巴嫩？
- We don't know for sure.
目前还不清楚确切地点
Check in while you're in the air.
途中再和你联系
Will do, General.
明白了，将军
Here you go, sweetheart.
给你钱，宝贝
Ladies and gentlemen,this is your new captain speaking.
女士们，先生们，现在是新机长向你们说话
My name is Abdul Rafai.
我叫阿布杜尔·拉菲
I am a member ofthe New World Revolutionary Organization.
我们是新世界革命组织的成员
We have declared war against the American imperialists,
我们已经向美帝国主义以及
Zionists, terrorists,and all other antisocialist atrocities.
犹太复国主义，恐怖主义和所有反社会主义的暴行宣战
Your plane is now headed for a new destination.
现在飞机正向新的目的地飞行
For your safety,I suggest you listen carefully
为了大家的安全，我建议大家听话
and you follow all instructions.
服从我们的命令
- Harry.
哈利
- What?
怎么了？
Harry, my ring. It's Hebrew.
哈利，我戒子上有希伯来文
Take it off. Put it in your purse.
把它脱下来，放到你的手提包里
Take it off.
脱下来
Harry, there's a white mark on my hand. You think they're gonna notice?
哈利，手指上有白色的字母印记，会被他们发现吗？
- Will you marry me?
你肯嫁给我吗？
Oh, Harry. What's gonna happen to us?
哦，哈利，知道会发生什么吗？
One thing is certain.
有一件事是肯定的
We'll always remember our silver wedding anniversary.
我们会永远记得我们的银婚纪念日的
[man] Let's do something.
想想办法
Yeah, it's only two of 'em. We can take 'em.
他们只有两个人，我们能解决他们
Sh! That's not a good idea. These guys are dangerous.
嘘，那不是个好主意，这些家伙很危险
Now, they're gonna blow this plane up.
要是他们炸毁飞机
There's a lot of people on this plane,and we just gotta play their game.
这架飞机上的人都会死，还是听他们的吧
All right.
都听着
You can all sit up now!
现在可以坐起来了
But nobody talks! Nobody move!
不许说话！不许乱动！
[man] Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
对不起，先生
- This young lady is preg...
这位女士怀孕了…
- Shut up!
闭嘴
Please, I'm not feeling well.
求你了，我现在难受极了
费耶特维尔 北卡罗亚纳州 麦考的农场
7月19日星期五凌晨2:42
An unidentified source at the State Department
国务院一位不愿透露姓名的人士
has just confirmed that an American airliner
表示一架
en route from Athens to Rome and New York
从雅典途经罗马飞抵纽约的美国航班
has just been hijacked.
被劫持
Over 100 Americans are believed to be on board the ATW airliner.
据称此次航班有超过100名美国乘客
We'll bring you further developments as they occur.
我们将跟随事态继续报道
In the meantime, none of the known terrorist groups in that region
目前，该地区尚无任何恐怖组织
are willing to take responsibility for this current action.
表示对此次行动负责
Now!
听着！
All men sit by the windows.
所有的男人都坐到窗口去
All women sit near the aisles! Do it now and quickly!
所有的女人都坐到通道边上的位置，快点
Just do it!
快点换！
Fast! Fast! And quiet!
快点！不许说话！
[man] You shut up. Nobody talk.
不许说话！
[woman on Tv] The hijacked plane is still in the air
被劫持飞机仍在飞行途中
heading for an unknown destination,
飞往未知目的地
presumably somewhere in the Middle East.
可能是中东某处
There is still no word
目前还不知道
on the condition ofthe Americans and the other hostages on board.
机上美国和其他人质的情况
We'll keep you updated
我们将向大家实时更新
as further information becomes available.
进一步的信息
Everyone get up and go into the back. Hurry up!
都给我到后面去，快去
Hurry up!
快！
We're coming. We're coming. It's all right.
我们走，我们走，好吧
Move! Move!
快！快！
- Excuse me. I left my purse.
对不起，我的包忘了！
- Leave it! Go!
走啊，走吧！
[man] Come on back. Keep movin'.Move. Come on, move.
到后面去，快点！快，快！
- Come on, move. Keep movin'.
快走，快走！
- Sit down!
坐下！
- I can't sit on the floor.
我不能坐在地板上呀！
- Sit!
坐下
My back.
我的背
Sit! Sit up there. Sit there. Sit.
坐下！坐那里，坐下！
- I'll sit on his lap.
我坐到他膝盖上去
- Thank you very much. Thank you.
谢谢，谢谢！
Sit down!
坐下！
- Watch that gun, sir. It might go off.
小心你的枪，先生，不然会走火的
- What'd you hit him for, man?
你为什么要打他，先生？
- Sit!
坐下！
Keep quiet. Silence.
不许说话，安静！
There's no space to breathe here.
这里挤得透不过气了
Shut up! Everyone, shut up!
住嘴！谁都不许说话！
Sit down!
坐下
[Deborah] Ellen! Come back here!
爱伦，快回来！
What are you doing here? Go back.
过来干什么？回去！
My doll.
我的娃娃！
It's a nice doll. What is your name?
这娃娃不错．你叫什么名字？
Ellen.
爱伦
Ellen. It's a very nice name.
爱伦．这名字很好听
How old are you, Ellen?
今年几岁了，爱伦？
Six.
六岁
You know, Ellen,
知道吗，爱伦
I had a daughter exactly your age. Her name was Salima.
我有个女儿和你年纪差不多，她叫萨利玛
You understand, Ellen?
听懂了吗，爱伦？
Good. Take it.
给，拿着
Thank you.
谢谢
Go, go. Go!
走，走吧
Come on.
来吧
浦帕空军基地
北卡罗来纳7月19日星期五凌晨3:00
Hey, Ace. You think the captain's gonna show up?
晦，艾斯,你说麦考上尉会来吗？
I'll be damned if he doesn't.
他不来我可惨了
Well, wasn't he called?
通知他了吗？
Well, who'd call him? He's retired to that old horse farm of his.
谁会通知麦考？他不是已经退役回他的老马牧场了吗？
Though, I must admit I wouldn't mind havin' Captain McCoy along.
反正他参不参加行动我都无所谓
I, uh, took the liberty of giving him a call, sir.
我已经通知过麦考了，长官
You what?
什么？
Well, he wasn't at home.
他不在家
Then he just might be on his way here, Colonel.
说不定他现在已经在路上了
Nah. None of that.
厄，不会
Now, that looks good.
那我们走着瞧
Oh, yeah.
好啊
Pull down the shades. Pull down the shades.
拉上窗帘，拉上窗帘
Put the shades down. All of you! Shades down.
拉上窗帘，都给我把窗帘拉上！
Pull them down!
拉上！
All right. Pull them down.All these window shades, pull them down.
好极了，所有的窗帘都给我拉上！
Pull the shades down. Come on.Pull the shades.
去拉上窗帘，快点，拉上窗帘
Pull these down.
拉上窗帘
阿布杜尔，过来
干什么？
快过来
什么东西？
看
这是希伯来文
飞机上有以色列人
Come here. Come here!
过来，这边来！
There are Israelis aboard this airplane. I want you to identify them for me.
这架飞机上有以色列人，你给我把他们全都找出来
We don't know who the Israelis are. How could we?
我不知道谁是以色列人，怎么找？
They came off the El Al flight, and I will find them.
他们是从别的航班转来的，我会查出他们的
Collect all passports.
把他们的护照都收来
- Why?
为什么？
- Do it!
去收！
OK.
好吧
Ladies and gentlemen, attention please.
女士们，先生们，请注意
They want all of you to turn in your passports.
他们要看你们的护照
So, please, get out your passports and hold them over your head.
所以请大家把护照举起来
- Why?
为什么？
- I don't know why.
我不知道
[woman] Thank you.
谢谢
Come on.
快去
穆斯塔法，盯着她
Just be quiet and do what they tell you to do.
请安静，照他们说的做
No, just women!You go back. Go back! Back!
不，只要女人！你们退回去，退后！
[woman] Miss, did they tell you why they want our passports?
小姐，他们说了为什么要收我们的护照吗？
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
[woman 2] Will we get them back? We need our passports.
他们会还给我们吗？我们还要用的
Put them here. Here.All of them. I want all of them.
放这儿，这儿．把护照全部收上来
No cheating. I know there are 144 passengers.
飞机上有144名乘客，别想骗我
Ingrid is getting the rest.
英格利特还在收呢
Excuse me, miss? Miss?
对不起，小姐，小姐？
Miss, we don't have passports. We're in the Navy.
小姐，我们没有护照，我们是美国海军
- We have these green Navy IDs.
我们只有绿色的海军证
- Hide them away.
把它们藏好
Hide it, man. Put it away.
藏起来，把它们放好
Hey, you. Why didn't you collect these men's passports?
晦，你，为什么不收他们的护照？
- They don't have passports.
他们没有护照
- It's impossible. You are lying.
这不可能，你在撒谎
No, wait a second. We have these.We have these.
等一等，我们有这个，我们有这个
- What is this?
这是什么？
- It's a Navy ID.
这是海军证
- Marines.
海军陆战队？
- No, Navy.
不，只是海军
We're divers for the American Navy.
我们是美国海军潜水员
- You?
你呢？
- All three of us. We're all Navy.
我们全是潜水员
Marines. American Marines.
海军陆战队，美国海军陆战队
American Marines killed many of my friends when they bombed Beirut.
美国海军陆战队，你们轰炸贝鲁特的时候，杀死了我好多朋友
America never bombed Beirut.
美国没有轰炸过贝鲁特
American planes from your ship New Jersey bombed our camps.
从新泽西号航空母舰上起飞的战机轰炸了我们的难民营
- Relax.
别激动．
- Son, you're making a mistake.
孩子，你说错了
America never bombed Beirut.
美国没有轰炸过贝鲁特
- Your American ship!
你们美国的航空母舰！
- No!
不！
Stop! He's a priest!
住手，他是神父！
够了，够了 !
这三个是美国海军陆战队的，看
Oh, yes? Three American heroes.
是吗？三个美国英雄
From now on, ou travel only first class, gentlemen.
从现在开始你们去头等舱，先生们
What's goin' on here?
来这儿干什么？
Shut up.
闭嘴！
- Why do you want us...
你们想要干什么…
- Just shut up!
快闭嘴！
Come here.
过来
Hold this.
拿好了
Please, just be quiet. OK?
请大家安静，好吗？
Everything will be all right.
一切都会好的
Listen. You don't have to do that.
听着，你们不必这样做
- We'll cooperate.
我们会合作的
- Shut up. Sit down.
你住嘴！坐下！
Sit down.
坐下
Now, you listen to me.
你听着，
Look at this passport one by one.
一本本检查这些护照
Pick out the passport with Jewish names.
把那些犹太名字的护照都找出来
American passports do not state religion.
美国护照不注明宗教和种族
Give me the Israelis.
那么找出以色列人
There are no Israelis onboard.
这飞机上没有以色列人
Then pick out the Jewish names.
那把有犹太名字的找出来
I told you, there is no way.I can know who is a Jew. How can I?
我跟你说过我不知道什么是犹太名字，让我怎么找？
Do it!
快找！
I can't! I won't do it!
这个事情我做不到
Yes, you will do it!
你能做到的！
No, not me!
我做不到！
Don't you see? I'm German!
你知道吗，我是德国人！
What does that mean?
这话什么意思？
The selections. The Nazis.
这种选择是纳粹干的
The death camps! Don't you see I can't do what you want me to do?
死亡集中营！这下你明白我为什么干不了了吧？
Very sorry, dear lady.
很抱歉，亲爱的小姐
But... you must do this for us.
但是，你必须为我们做这件事
You claim you belong to a revolutionary organization.
你们不是自称为世界革命组织吗？
That is correct.We are freedom fighters.
说得对，我们都是自由战士
We are fighting for our brothers.
我们为自己的兄弟而战
But then you don't want to be associated with Nazis
那为什么你们的所作所为像纳粹？
who killed six million Jews.
他们杀死了600万犹太人
Not enough, lady. Not enough.
远远不够，小姐，还远远不够！
The Jews stole Palestine. They took our lands.
以色列占领了巴勒斯坦，他们夺走了我们的土地
Leave her alone! Without that gun,you wouldn't be shit!
你的枪离她远点，小心走火！
- Shut up, you American imperialist pig!
闭嘴，你这个美国猪！
- Stop it, please!
住手，别打了！
- You are all pigs and killers.
一你们这群猪，杀人凶手
- Don't let him kill him!
一别让他杀死他！
- Don't let him kill him, please.
求你了，别让他打死他
- Stop him! Don't let him kill him!
住手！别让他打死他！
- Bitch!
去你的
- [Mustafa] Pig!
猪！
- [Ingrid] Please!
求你别打了！
You will do what Abdul said.
你要按阿布杜尔说的去做
He is your new captain,and you obey or you die.
他是新机长，你不服从就去死
You hear me? You die.
你是做呢还是想死？
We will kill everyone on this bloody plane.
我们会杀掉这飞机上所有的人
No, I won't do it!
不！我决不干这种事！
Yes!
你敢！
What's going on, Colonel?
准备得怎么样了，上校？
Men and equipment are aboard. What's the delay?
人员和装备都登机了，为什么推迟起飞？
I'll give him five more minutes.
我再给他五分钟时间
- Who?
谁？
- Oh, nothing, sir.
哦，没什么，长官
Just a few more minutes.
只延迟几分钟而已
Colonel?
上校
Well, it's about time you showed up.
你来得真是时候
I was afraid I was gonna have to use this.
我恐怕必须用这个了
What is it?
这是什么？
A presidential decree ordering you back to duty.
这是总统的命令，要求你归队
And you can leave the keys in the van, too.
你该把钥匙留在车里了
I've got your gear on the plane. General, we're all set.
我已经在机上准备了你的装备，将军，一切就绪
Good luck, Colonel.
祝你好运，上校
- How was your engagement party?
你的订婚晚会怎样？
- Well, it was a little cut short.
时间确实紧了点
- Bobby, good to see you.
波比，很高兴又见到你
- Welcome back, boss.
欢迎回来，头
- Do you know who that guy is?
你认识那个家伙吗？
- No.
不认识
- Well, let's go do it.
那好，我们走吧
- Let's do it.
我们走
- Great to see you.
见到你真高兴
- Good to see you, Captain Jack.
很高兴见到你，杰克上尉
Remember, I don't want to carry your ass this time.
还记得吗？这次我不必背你这混蛋了
- No way, Captain.
说不定，上尉
- Major.
少校
Yes, sir, Major.
是，长官，少校
Major.
少校
- What the hell, huh?
感觉怎么样？
- Congratulations.
恭喜你！
- Thanks.
谢谢
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your new captain speaking.
女士们，先生们，我是你们的新机长
Miss Ingrid will read some names.
英格瑞特小姐会念一些名字
- If your name is called...
如果念到你的名字…
- What are they doing?
他要干什么？
...come immediately to first class cabin.
…请立刻到头等舱里来
I repeat, immediately.
我再说一遍，立刻来
Kaplan, Benjamin.Mr. Benjamin Kaplan.
卡普兰·本杰明，本杰明·卡普兰先生
This can't be happening.Not now, not again.
这不是真的，不是
Not again.
不是真的
What are you doing? Where are you going? Don't go.
你要干什么？你去哪儿？别去
We... We survived once.
我从集中营生还了
We can do it again.
就能再一次回来
I'm coming.
我来了
Where are you going? Go back to your seat.
你干什么？回你的座位去！
He is my husband.
他是我丈夫
Sit down!
坐下！
No. No. I won't listen.
不，我不想听你的
No, I won't. Go on! Listen! Why don't you all do something?
不！我不怕！听着！为什么你们大家不起来反抗呢？
There's only two of them! There's so many of you! Why don't you?
他们只有两个人，而你们有这么多人，为什么不反抗？
I don't care.
我不怕！
[woman] She's just upset.
她头脑混乱了
No, it's the war!
不，这是一场战争
It's the war all over again! The concentration camps!
这是又一场战争！又一个集中营！
Why don't you do something? Something!
大家为什么不想想办法呢？
- There's only two of them!
他们只有两个人！
- [Mustafa] Sit down!
坐下！
And there's so many of us!
而我们有这么多人
- Do something!
干吧，
- Please...
求你们了
You! Sit down! Sit!
你给我坐下！
I'm Benjamin Kaplan.
我是本杰明·卡普兰
What can I do for you?
你有什么事吗？
Sit down.
坐下
Next one.
下一个
Harry Goldman.
哈利·戈德曼
[Ingrid] Mr. Harry Goldman, come to first class, please.
哈利·戈德曼先生，请到头等舱来
Please. Don't take him, please.
请你们不要带他去
He's a sick man. He has a heart condition.
他是个病人，他有心脏病
- Sylvia. Sylvia, be strong.
西尔维娅，坚强些！
- Please no!
别去！
Listen to me. Be strong. I'm OK.
听我说，坚强点，我没事
- Please don't go!
请别走！
- I can go. I can go. It's OK.
让我去，我不会有事的
- It's OK.
没事的
- [Mustafa] Move.
快走！
- It's OK.
我没事的
[Mustafa] Go!
走！
- Harry Goldman.
哈利·戈德曼
- Sit.
坐下
Next.
下一个
Robert Levine.
罗伯特·列文
Mr. Robert Levine, please come to first class, please.
罗伯特·列文先生，请到头等舱来
OK, OK. Move, move. Move.
行了，行了，走吧，走吧
[sobbing] Please don't take my daddy.
请你不要把我爸爸带走
Daddy, take me with you!
爸爸我要和你一起走
I have to go, sweetheart. But I'm not leaving the plane.
我必须去，宝贝，我还在飞机上嘛
- He can't, sweetie. Daddy can't...
他不能带你去，宝贝．爸爸，不…
- I'm not leaving the plane.
我还在飞机上呢
I'll be back.
我就会回来的
Daddy. Here, take.
爸爸，带上娃娃
OK, move! Move, move!
好了，快走，快走！
Move, move!
走，走
Go, go, go, go. Move, move, move!
走，走，快！
You just keep your hands off my daughter.
不许伤害我的女儿
Move.
走
On the floor.
坐在地上
David Rosovsky.
戴维·洛索夫斯基
Mr. Rosovsky, come to first class, please.
洛索夫斯基先生请到头等舱来
They're making a mistake. They're making a mistake.
他们搞错了，他们一定是搞错了
Mr. Rosovsky, you move or I shoot you right here.
洛索夫斯基先生，快走，要不我就杀了你
But I am not Jewish. I'm an American.
但我不是犹太人，我是美国人
I came from Russia, but now I live in America.
我出生在俄罗斯，但我现在生活在美国啊
I am Christian Orthodox. Ask them. Sister, tell him I am not a Jew.
我信仰的是东正教，你可以问问他们 女士，告诉他我不是犹太人
Father, don't you know me from Chicago?
神父，你不是在芝加哥就认识我的吗？
- Move!
走！
- [Sister] Wait.
等等
Wait. This man is telling the truth.
等等，这个人说的是真话
- He's telling the truth.
他说的是真话
- Sit down. We know what we are doing.
坐下！我们知道怎么做
Sir, you are making a big mistake...
先生，你们犯了个大错…
Sit down. On the floor!
坐下，坐地板上
- He is telling the truth.
他说的是真话
- Sit down. We know what we are doing.
坐下！我们知道怎么做
Father, where are you going?
神父，你到哪儿去？
You, come back!
你，回来！
Come back! I said come back!
回来，我说了，你回来！
No!
不！
Sit down!
坐下！
- What are you doing here?
你来这里干什么？
- You called me.
你叫我来的
- What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
- William O'Malley.
威廉姆·奥马利
- I did not call you.
我没有叫你
- You called for all the Jews.
可你叫犹太人啊
I'm Jewish, just like Jesus Christ.
我是犹太人，就像耶稣一样
You take one of us, you gotta take us all.
和这里所有的犹太人一样
Sit down, then.
那你坐吧
- You.
你
- Me?
我？
Yeah. The pregnant lady. Come on. Come on.
对，你不是怀孕了吗？过来
Excuse me.
对不起
You, go, go, go. Move. Come, come.
你们，起来，到后面去，快
I need some pillows. Give me some pillows.
我要一些枕头，拿几个枕头来
Come, come, come.
来，来，来
Yeah... Sit down. Sit.
好的…坐下
OK, that's enough. Sit. That's enough. Sit down.
好，够了，够了，你们坐下
- You feel good? Yes?
你感觉好些吗？
- Fine. Thank you for remembering.
很好，谢谢你还记得我
- OK everything? Yeah? Good.
一切都好？很好
- Thank you.
谢谢你
- Sleep well.
睡个好觉
- Thanks.
谢谢
[Roger] Beirut approach control, American Travelways flight 282,
贝鲁特机场，这里是美航282航班
under command of Captain Abdul Rafai
由机长阿布杜尔·拉菲领导
of the New...
属于新…
World Revolution.
世界革命
...World Revolution requesting landing instructions.
…新世界革命，我们请求着陆
American Travelway, I am unable to give you landing instruction.
美航282，我们不能接受你的着陆请求
This airport is closed today to all international flights
本机场今天对所有国际航班关闭
by order of the Lebanese government.
这是黎巴嫩政府的命令
You heard the man. Now what do you want to do?
你听到了吧，现在怎么办？
Land.
降落
Damn.
见鬼
Beirut, you must clear that runway at once, or we'll all die.
贝鲁特，请马上清理跑道，不然我们全完了
You are facing disaster if you try to land.
如果你们强行着陆，后果不堪设想
Just a minute.
请等一下
飞机在哪儿？
在那儿
你和机长联系过了？让我和他通话
Captain? Captain, this is the Minister of Defense speaking.
机长，机长，我是黎巴嫩国防部长
You cannot land in our country.
你们不能在我国降落
We have enough trouble without you people.
就是没有你们这帮人，我们的麻烦也够多的了
We have 144 men, women, and children aboard this aircraft.
机上有144名乘客，包括妇女和儿童
The hijacker has threatened to blow us up.
劫机者威胁说要炸机
But if he does, it'll be your responsibility.
如果他这么做，你们将对此负责
Do you understand that, Mr. Minister? Do we now have your permission to land?
你明白吗，部长先生？现在同意我们降落了吧？
My answer is definitely not.
我的回答是绝对不同意
部长先生…部长先生…
…你听
什么事情？
Captain, Captain, what's this shouting? What's going on there?
机长，这是什么声音？发生了什么事情？
They're torturing a young boy. A Navy hostage.
他们在毒打一个男孩，美国海军的潜水员
They're killing him.
他们会杀了他
Mr. Minister, we're coming in for landing
部长先生，我要降落了
whether we have your permission or not.
不管你们同意或是不同意
Reducing power.
减速
让他们降落
Captain, it's OK. You have permission to land.
机长，听到吗？你们已被准许降落
Butjust give me a minute. I want to clear the runway.
请稍等片刻，我们马上清理跑道
穿越大西洋
7月19日星期五凌晨5:45
[Nick] All right, gentlemen.
各位
We'll go in three sections. McCoy, you'll lead the first section.
我们现在要分成三组，麦考带领第一组
I want you to hit the emergency exits on the port wing, here and here,
我要你快速从左翼攻入，这儿还有这儿
clearing the first-class cabin and the cockpit.
夺取驾驶舱和头等舱
Pete, you'll have the second section. I want you to hit the emergency exits
彼德率领第二组，要求动作迅速
on the starboard wing, here, clearing the main cabin.
从右翼进攻，夺取主舱
Bobby, you'll have section three for backup and emergencies.
波比带第三组作为预备队，应对紧急情况
Move fast. It should be a piece of cake. There are only two terrorists onboard.
记住动作要干净利落，飞机上只有2名恐怖分子
How do we know that?
你怎么知道？
A calculated guess.
这是我的推算
All right, gentlemen. Any questions?
好了，各位，还有什么问题吗？
黎巴嫩
贝鲁特机场7月19日星期五中午
Please help yourself.
请喝吧
告诉美国人，每五分钟…
我们就会杀一个人质
他们每五分钟就杀一个人质
这将是一场惨剧
贾米尔，感谢上帝，你终于来了
每五分钟他们就要杀一个人质
让我来试试？
我试试
晦，兄弟
贾米尔
祝贺你
现在我们需要世界的同情
也需要美国民众的同情
我们应该联合起来
你先释放妇女和儿童
然后美国政府就会和你谈判
不
听我说，兄弟
我是你们的指挥官
现在已经不是了
阿布都尔，我们都是为同一个理想而战
不是！给我们加油！
谈崩了？
他们是在自杀
给他们加油，让他们走
好吧，阿布都尔，用你的方式去完成使命吧
神和你同在
Mama, it's so hot.
妈妈，好热呀
I know, sweetie. Everybody's hot.
我知道，宝贝，大家都热
What are they doing there with Daddy?
他们会对爸爸怎么样？
[sighs] Asking him some questions.
问他一些问题吧
What kind of questions?
什么问题呀
Maybe, uh... about being Jewish.
也许是关于犹太人的
They don't like Jews, huh, Mama?
他们不喜欢犹太人吗，妈妈？
No, sweetie, they don't like Jews.
是的，宝贝，他们不喜欢犹太人
Open the door. Open the door. Open.
开门，快开门，快！
哈桑
穆斯塔法，你好吗
You move, move, move. Sit down.
你走开，走开，去坐着
恭喜你了，兄弟
见到你们真高兴
把头套摘掉
- Father, God be with you.
神父，上帝与你同在
- Take care of yourself, Sister.
你们自己多保重，女士
Take care of them.
照顾好他们
You stay.
你留下
Ben.
本
Don't take him, please.
求求你，别把他带走
Daddy. Mommy, they're taking Daddy.
爸爸！妈妈他们把爸爸带走了
No!
不！
Move, move.
快，快
All right, time to leave. We take off.
行了，可以走了，马上起飞
Where to?
飞哪儿？
I will let you know when we reach the sky.
升空后我会告诉你的
贝鲁特
市中心 恐怖分子总部
7月19日星期五下午2:00
把他们关起来
走！快点！
[man] We've been informed by Israeli Intelligence
我们从以色列的情报获悉
that they've left Beirut and are headed towards North Africa.
被劫飞机已经离开贝鲁特，正在向北非飞行
We have reason to believe they're on their way to Algiers.
我们有理由相信，他们将飞往阿尔及尔
If so, they'll be landing at Boumediene Airport in four hours.
如真是这样，他们将于4小时后抵达博美丁机场
[man] Nick, I've just had confirmation from the president.
尼克，我刚才从总统那里证实
The Algerian government is ready to cooperate. You can go to Algiers.
阿尔及利亚政府同意与我们合作，所以你们可以在阿尔及利亚降落
[Scott] All right, guys. Listen up.
好了，伙计们，都听到了
We're landing in Algiers. Prepare your gear.
我们要在阿尔及尔降落，整理好你们的装备
Algiers, this is Delta One requesting permission to land.
阿尔及尔，这里是三角洲一号，请允许降落
Delta One, this is Boumediene International Airport.
三角洲一号，我是博美丁国际机场
Permission granted.
同意降落
American Travelways flight 282, this is Boumediene Algiers Airport.
美航282航班注意，我是阿尔及尔博美丁国际机场
You are cleared to land.
同意你们降落
So you men stay with the equipment.
你们在这看好装备
We are gonna go for it this time, right, Colonel?
看来这次我们要大干一场了，是吗，上校？
Damn right.
当然
This is Delta One. I receive you. Delta One, I receive you.
这里是三角洲一号．我听见了，三角洲一号，我听见了
Yes, sir. Just a minute, sir.
是，长官，请等一下
Colonel. Colonel, General Woodbridge, sir.
上校，上校，伍布里奇将军
General Woodbridge, we've got damn near perfect conditions now.
将军，目前这里的情况和我们预计的一样
It's just the situation we've been waiting for.
是采取行动的好机会
Ifwe wait any longer, we can end up with another fiasco.
要是再等下去很可能前功尽弃
I'm sorry, Nick. The president doesn't want to risk any lives.
对不起，尼克，总统不希望有人员伤亡
If he can release our people through negotiations,
如果通过谈判能使人质获释
that's what he wants to do.
他认为就不必使用武力
So until the negotiations break down...
等谈判彻底破裂了…
...your people are on hold.
…会通知你们的
How long do we have to wait?
要等多久？
Well, General Woodbridge is waiting for the go-ahead from the president.
伍布里奇将军说，要等总统下命令
I'm waiting for the go-ahead from General Woodbridge,
我在等伍布里奇将军的命令
and you're waiting for the go-ahead from me, clear?
而你要等我下命令，懂吗？
In the meantime, I'm going over to the terminal.
我现在到总部去一趟
I wanna debrief any hostages that are released,
打听打听飞机上的那些人质
if and when any are released.
有没有什么新的情况
So you get out there. And get set.
你们先去那儿，等我命令
- But wait for my signal.
你可不能乱来
- Got it.
知道了
OK, get rid of the box.
好了，都放回去
Move out.
出发
Captain Rafai, the flight from Athens has just landed.
拉菲机长，雅典来的客机马上就要降落
Your comrade will be with you any moment.
你的同志马上就能与你会合
We expect you to release the women and children without any more delays.
希望你们尽快释放妇女儿童，不要拖延
[Abdul] We shall keep our word as promised, Mr. Ambassador.
我们一定会信守诺言的，大使先生
All right, Colonel, I'm gonna go to the plane.
就这样，上校，我到飞机上去了
I'll wait for you here, Mr. Ambassador.
我在这儿等你，大使先生
You send back any hostage from that plane that speaks English.
你尽快找一个会说英语的人质到这儿来
McCoy, nobody moves until all the women and children are safe.
麦考，不许乱来，要确保所有妇女和儿童的安全
All sections, acknowledge. One, two and three.
第一，第二，第三小组都明白了吗？
兄弟，见到你真高兴
You wait. You get women and children.
你等着，你会得到妇女和孩子们的
最近怎么样，贾法尔
行动进行得如何
一切都很顺利
我们要不要释放女人和孩子
是的
Please, let him go.
请你放了他吧
He's almost dead.
他快要死了
No.
不行
But you may go. I release you with the women.
但你可以走，我把你和那些妇女都放走
Go.
走
Ingrid...
英格瑞
You're a brave woman.
你是个勇敢的女人
Section one in position.
第一组就位
Section two in position.
第二组就位
Section three in position.
第三组就位
We don't move until the women and children are away and safe.
妇女儿童安全离开之前不要行动
- Acknowledge, section two.
第二组明白吗？
- Section two acknowledge.
第二组明白
Section three?
第三组？
Section three acknowledge.
第三组明白
Ladies and children, Allah be praised.
女士们和孩子们，感谢真主
It is time to leave the airplane. Men will stay in their seats.
你们可以离开飞机了,男人们留下，坐在自己座位上
We will ask you to have your valuables, your money, yourjewelry
我们要求你们把贵重物品，比如金钱，珠宝等留下
out in your hands so that we may collect them
在你们经过头等舱时
when you come through the first-class cabin.
我们会接收它们
Go on, sweetie. You go ahead. Come on.
走吧，宝贝，你先走，快
We'll see you later.
好吧，再见
Jay, you take care of your mom. You understand me?
孩子，照顾好妈妈，明白吗？
You ladies, go forward. Everyone forward.
你过来，都过来
- Leave it with you.
把这留下来，
- Move forward, Christian ladies.
朝前走，基督徒女士
Why are you behaving like common bandits?
你们怎么像土匪一样？
You're freedom fighters, aren't you?
你们还算是自由战士吗？
Go.
走
Move.
快走
Go. Go.
走，走
I take this... and this...
我脱下这个…还有这个…
I have some money.
还有些钱
- This is yours?
这个是你的？
- Yes.
是的
Thank you.
谢谢
- You have some money? OK, go.
你还有钱吗？好，走
- Here.
还有这个
Go. Go.
走，走
Thank God the women are safe.
感谢上帝，妇女们都平安了
Yeah.
是我
Nick, the bus has left. We're ready to make our move.
上校，大巴走了，我们该行动了
Sorry, McCoy. We're still on hold.
不行，麦考，我们还得再等等
Damn it, Nick. Let's not screw this one up.
妈的，别又像上回那样
Everyone to the back! To the back!
都到后面去，到后面去！
- [man] Colonel Alexander?
亚历山大上校？
- Yeah.
在
They want you on the phone.
有你的电话
Alexander here.
我是亚历山大
Nick, it's a go.
上校，行动吧
Gotcha.
知道了
McCoy, it's a go. Take 'em down.
麦考，开始行动，消灭他们
OK, section two and three, let's do it. Close communications.
第二，第三小组，我们准备行动，关掉通讯设备
We go in... 60 seconds.
我们再等60秒钟
Ready? Mark.
明白吗？请回话
Mark. We go in 60 seconds.
明白，再等60秒钟
Sixty seconds. Mark.
再等60秒，明白
Radios off the air.
关掉对讲机
Colonel, this is Ingrid Harding, she's the plane's purser.
上校，她叫英格瑞·哈丁，她是空中小姐
Mr. Ambassador, excuse me. I'd like to talk to her alone.
大使先生，能不能让我和她单独谈谈
- Yes, sir.
当然可以
- Thank you.
谢谢
Miss Harding, this will only take a few minutes.
英格瑞小姐，打扰你几分钟
What's happening?
什么事？
The Algerian commandos are gonna break into the plane.
美国特种部队想袭击飞机
Oh, no. Don't.
噢，不，不行
All the hostages in Beirut, they'll kill them all.
所有在贝鲁特的人质都会送命的
What hostages?
什么人质？
The guys from the Navy and all the Jews they took off the plane
两个美国海军和所有犹太人，在其他劫机者上来时
when the other hijackers came on.
都被带下飞机了
- What other hijackers?
还有劫机者？
- All those men who came on board.
在贝鲁特上来的
Ten or 12 of them.
大概有10到12个人
Oh, God. All sections, all sections.
上帝啊，各小组注意，各小组注意
OK, 30 seconds. All right?
还有30秒钟，是吗？
All sections! Come on, somebody respond.
各小组注意！快！怎么没人回答？
Let's go. Turn the light on. Hit the siren.
快走，打开警灯，拉响警笛
- All sections.
各小组注意
What the hell is that?
这是怎么回事？
Come on, get out of there, McCoy.
快撤啊，麦考
McCoy!
麦考！
Turn the lights! Turn the lights out!
快关上灯！关灯！
- What the hell?
见鬼！
Don't shoot back! We're clearing out! Get out!
别开枪，我们撤！快撤！
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
别开枪，别开枪
- Get out. Get out of the tanker.
快撤！把油罐车开走！
Oh, shit.
哦，天哪！
Take off immediately! Take off!
马上起飞！起飞！
- All right, all right.
知道了，
- Take off!
起飞！
[speaking foreign language]
Come. Come.
快，快
Americans, look what you have done!
美国老，看看你们这样做的后果！
Look here, Americans! Look!
看这儿，美国佬，看这儿！
He's gonna kill him.
他会杀了他
Now your American president will know we are serious!
现在美国总统就会明白，我们是说到做到的
- Here is a token for him...
这是为他和…
- Don't shoot.
别开枪
...and the American people.
…美国人准备的
- One Marine killer!
一个海军陆战队杀手！
Oh, Jesus.
哦，天哪！
Son of a bitch. Let's go.
狗杂种，我们走
Come on, move.
走吧，快！
Sorry I had to do it that way, boys.
抱歉，孩子们，我不得不采取这样的方法
It was the only way I could stop you in time.
这是唯一能及时阻止你们的办法
What happened, Colonel?
怎么回事，上校
Twelve terrorists got on board.
12个恐怖分子登上了飞机
They were in every corner of that plane with machine guns.
他们手持机关枪，遍布飞机上各个角落
It would've been a disaster.
我们冲进去就会闯祸的
He's an American. He was in the Navy.
他是美国人，美国海军潜水员
Where do we go from here?
下一步怎么办？
After them, I hope.
我想去追踪他们
They're going back to Beirut.
他们正飞回贝鲁特
You mean it's all over for us?
你是说没有我们的事了
On the contrary, Colonel.
事情还没有完，上校
The president wants you to fly to Israel.
总统要你们飞往以色列
Israel?
去以色列？
[man] Israel is America's best friend in the Middle East,
以色列是美国在中东的盟友
and it's only 20 minutes from Beirut.
而且到贝鲁特只有20分钟的航程
You're gonna get anything and everything you want to do it right.
在那里你们可以得到一切援助
The president wants those people home.
总统决心要救出这些人质
So do we, General. So do we.
我们也是，将军，我们也决心要救出人质
We are Americans. Stay down.
我们是美军，快趴下！
- Clear.
行了，
- Clear!
行了
Not bad, McCoy. Not bad. Twenty seconds. Just like clockwork.
不错，麦考，只用了20秒钟，真不赖啊
- We can do it in ten.
应该只用十秒钟好，
- All right, one more time.
再来一次
以色列
空军基地7月20日星期六上午5:50
Hold it, McCoy. We got visitors.
等一下，麦考，我们有客人
- Colonel Alexander?
你是亚历山大上校吗？
- Yeah.
我是
Good morning. I'm Colonel Amir from the Israeli Intelligence.
早上好，我是以色列情报局的阿米尔上校
Oh, yes. How are you? This is Major McCoy.
你好，这是麦考少校
- Good morning, Major.
你好，少校
- Colonel.
你好，上校
- Can I talk to you?
上校，能和你谈谈吗？
- Well, certainly.
当然可以
Bobby, take over. I want it done in ten seconds.
波比，你来指挥，10秒钟内完成
- You got it, sir.
明白了，
- We'll be right down.
我们这就下来
[Nick] So, what's happening?
出了什么事？
[Amir] They've taken the hostages off the plane.
他们把人质带离了飞机
- [Nick] Where to?
带哪儿去了？
- [Amir] I don't know.
这还不清楚
They could be spreading them all over Beirut by now.
他们现在大概被分散藏在贝鲁特各处
[Scott] That's bad.
糟糕
Colonel, I assume your Mossad still has people planted in Lebanon, right?
我想，你们摩萨德在黎巴嫩一定有许多特工吧
Your assumption is correct.
你猜得很对
I need to get in contact with one of them.
我想和他们联系一下
You mean you want to get in and do some reckoning before the rescue?
你的意思是在行动之前去查看一下地形
It'd be a great help to us, Colonel.
这将是对我们莫大的帮助，上校
If I may suggest...
我想起来…
They've announced an international press conference.
他们宣布说要举行一个新闻发布会
Of course. Now that they got the world's attention,
当然，现在他们受到了全世界的关注
they wanna manipulate the press. Perfect.
他们想操纵新闻，这是最好的方法
贝鲁特
地中海海滨7月20日星期六上午8:00
让开，让他们进去，快点
快把床垫放进去
把他们喂拘
默罕默德，去加强守卫，快！
又是一场葬礼
又是一个基督教徒
I was in Beirut 20 years ago. You should have been here then.
20年之前我曾住在贝鲁特，现在你们也来这儿了
It was something.
这儿有什么
They had everything: nightclubs, dancing, concerts, laughter.
他们什么都有：夜总会，舞厅，演唱会，笑声
It was the Las Vegas of the Middle East.
曾被称为中东的拉斯维加斯
Beirut was beautiful then. Beautiful.
那时的贝鲁特是那么美
我不喜欢这个
你不喜欢什么？
这个基督教区
那个教堂？它早就在这里了
你要我们去摧毁它妈？
这个神父怎么样？
那个希腊人？
他从建这教堂起就在这儿了
他是个神父又是朋友，我们不能伤害他
我不信任这个基督徒
Hey, Marine heroes.
晦，陆战队英雄
Your friend.
你们的朋友
He made the news.
他上了新闻
They killed him. They killed Tom.
他们杀了他，他们杀了汤姆
贝鲁特机场
7月22日星期一上午10:00
How have they been treating you, Captain?
他们有没有虐待你们，机长？
- Sh!
厄
- Quite well.
还不错
They're feeding us. They're letting us use the rest rooms.
他们为我们提供了食物和日用品还让我们使用休息室
I suppose, under the circumstances, they're treating us quite well.
我想，在这样的状况下，他们待我们还算不错
Where are the others? Where do they keep the Jews?
其他的人呢？他们还关着犹太人吗？
It's true about the selection?
关于有区别的对待是真的吗？
Go back!
往后退！
One more question!
还有一个问题！
If you try to be clever with me, Captain, I will kill you.
如果你想跟我玩花招，我会杀了你
That'd make you a real hero, wouldn't it?
那你就真成了英雄了是吗？
Yes, yes.
对，没错
Now, you go back to the press, but you watch what you say, huh?
现在继续回答记者的问题，但说话要小心
Now, ask your questions, please. One at a time.
现在请继续提问吧，每人一次
先生，请检查你的箱子…
相机也要检查
请出示护照
加拿大人，是的，加拿大CBC电视台的
今天似乎全世界的电视台都到这儿来了
Belt.
皮带
抱歉
没事了
行了，没事了
祝你们在黎巴嫩过得愉快
谢谢
Where'd you get the stupid belt?
你这烂皮带哪来的？
You gave it to me for my birthday.
是你送我的生日礼物
I did? I hope you like it.
是吗？希望你喜欢
[priest] So you're Canadian.
这么说，你们是加拿大人
You're blessed with a beautiful and peaceful country.
你们很幸运，加拿大是一个美丽祥和的国家
I'd like to go there myself one day.
但愿哪天我也能去看看
Well, it's a beautiful country here. It's a shame.
这个国家也很美啊，可惜了
Do you know where we need to go?
你知道我们要去哪儿吗？
Yes, my son. We're on our way.
是的，孩子，我正朝那儿去呐
You'll need these.
你拿着这个
If you look down to your right, you'll see the main sewer pipe.
你朝右边看，可以看见一排主水管
It will lead you directly to the backyard of the school.
它直接通到学校的后院
That is where most of the hostages are.
大多数人质都关在那里
Their headquarters. The Jews are there. Do you want to come with me?
他们的总部．犹太人就关在那里，你们要跟我去看看吗？
No, go and do what you have to do.
不了，你忙你的去吧
Under the seat you'll find something you might need... just in case.
座位下面有你们需要的东西…千万小心
Don't take too long.
别去太久
Boss, aren't we trusting this guy a bit too much?
头，你对他是否过于信任了
The Israelis say he's the best man they have in Lebanon.
以色列方面说，他是他们在黎巴嫩最得力的人
And we need someone to get the message back to Nick.
而且我们必须通过他和尼克联系
神父
孩子，上帝将宽怒你
走
Boss. Boss, look.
头，你看
We'd better get outta here.
我们最好赶快离开
Wait.
等等
守在这儿
Go! Go! Go! Go!
走，走，走，快走
Go!
快走！
Jesus Christ, what do we do now?
天哪，现在怎么办？
快抓住他们
Get the hell outta here.
快离开这鬼地方
Shit.
见鬼
You OK, Butch?
你没事吧，巴奇
Yeah, I'm OK, boss.
我没事，头
Shit, that was a close one, huh?
妈的，真是太危险了
[Nick] It's already 4:15.
已经四点十五分了
We had him on the radio.
我们在无线电中听到过他的信号
He started to say something. Then we lost him.
他刚开始说话就中断了
Well, I can't wait any longer.
我们不能再等了
This is Mr. Samir, your guide in Beirut.
这是沙米尔，去贝鲁特的向导
Oh, good. We gotta get moving.
好，我们得马上出发
Otherwise, we're gonna miss that rendez-vous.
否则就没法和麦考会合了
以色列
海法海军基地7月22日星期一下午4:15
[Nick] Uh, Raffi, I just want to thank you for all your help on this.
拉菲，感谢你们这次的通力合作
I wish I could join you.
我也很希望能参加
Well, you boys have done it before. Now it's our turn.
你们的任务已经完成，现在轮到我们了
Good luck.
祝你好运
[Nick] All right, check your gear, boys: all the vehicles, weaponry, personal.
好了，大家检查一下各自携带的武器装备
Let's go.
出发
Aw, Jesus, boss. She's had it. We need another vehicle here.
糟了，头，它动不了啦，我们得换辆新车
We've got one.
有了
Here are some blankets for the night.
这些毛毯给你们过夜
How about some beds?
有没有床？
You don't need beds. You're gonna die tomorrow.
用不着床了，明天你们就没命了
Scott, that must be them.
一定是上校他们
About a mile off shore, I'd say.
离岸大约还有一海里
- You OK?
还好吗？
- Yeah. You?
还好，你呢？
Yeah, good to be on dry land. How we doing?
上岸就好了，情况怎么样？
Well, we have three targets.
人质被关在三个地方
A school in the northern part of Beirut beach. 60 hostages are there.
贝鲁特北部的一所学校里大约有60名人质
Do you know where that is?
你认识那地方吗？
Is it the one by the Greek Orthodox cemetery?
在一所希腊东正教堂的墓地旁边
- Yeah, right.
好，
- I got it.
我知道了
And the Jews are being held in a dungeon at their headquarters.
犹太人质被关在恐怖分子总部
It's in the center of town. You know where it's at, right?
那是在市中心，彼德认识那地方
- Yes, sir.
我认识，长官
- Good.
好
And the ATW crew is still being held on the plane.
机组人员还在飞机上
We'll have to get them last.
我们最后去救他们
Right. And I drew a map here.
对了，我画了一张地图
All right, everybody. Get your badges on.
全体人员注意，戴上标志
We move out in two minutes.
两分钟以后出发
Let's go right, partner.
我们向右转
阿布都尔，快起床
什么事？
他们来了
谁？
美国人
全都起床，快！
都跟我来
把人质都带来
好
上帝与我们同在
感谢上帝
快，开始行动，快！
That's the place.
就是这儿了
[man] Good luck.
好运
一切都正常吧？
没问题
他们吃了没有
他们吃完就去睡觉了
Why do you look at me like that?
你为什么这样看着我？
You hate me, huh?
你恨我，是吗？
It's your government we fight, not you. It's your White House.
我们是和你们的政府作战，不是和你,是对你们白宫的那帮家伙
One day I will go there.
总有一天我会去那里
I will drive a truck,
我将开一辆卡车去
and truck, it will blow.
而卡车将会爆炸
That'll be suicide. You know that.
那叫自杀式攻击，你明白吗？
I know how to die.
我知道怎样去死
The White House is a very big place. You'll need a lot of explosives.
白宫范围很大，你得用大量的炸药
You'll never get near the place. Don't kid yourself.
你根本无法接近白宫，别做白日梦了
Do you think we don't have friends in America?
你认为我在美国就没有朋友吗？
You will be surprised.
你一定会大吃一惊
One day. One day.
会有那一天的
Delta Two in position.
第二组已经准备完毕
Ready, boss?
行了吗？
Let's do it.
干吧
你们听见什么声音没有？
没，只有我掷骰子的声音
Cover us.
掩护我们
One minute to showtime.
一分钟以后行动
Get ready.
准备完毕
OK, 30 seconds to blastoff.
离引爆还有30秒
Come on, McCoy.
开始吧，麦考
Sleep tight, sucker.
好好睡吧，混蛋
Backyard, Bobby. Nick's waiting with the truck.
波比，到后院去，尼克的车在等着你呢
Right, boss. Gentlemen, let's go. Segal, take the rear.
知道了，头，大家快走，西格尔把守后面
Stop him!
拦住他
呼叫总部
我是司令，别吵
什么事
美国人来了
这儿搅得一团糟
他们是些什么人
美国人
他们开着吉普和坦克来围剿我们了
穆斯塔法在哪儿...还有你们的长官呢？
人质在哪儿
杀光这些美国人
美国人正在杀光我们
我5分钟内前来增援
我们等不及了，我们等不及了
- Hey.
晦
- Ah!
啊
萨利姆，萨利姆，能听见吗？
萨利姆，发生什么事了？
American?
美国人？
American, do you hear me? I want to talk to you.
美国人，你听到吗？我要跟你谈谈
American? I want to negotiate.
美国人，我要和你谈判
Do you hear me, American?
你听到了吗，美国人？
Loud and clear.
听得很清楚
快点！
Come on, hurry.
跟上，快点！
- Get back!
快回去！
My leg!
我的腿！
[man] All right, get down! Here I come. Hold on to me.
我的腿完了！来，扶住我
Hold on. I got you.
抓紧了，我抓住了
- Let me help. I'm a medical student.
我来看看，我是医学院的学生
- All right.
好的
He'll need help with circulation.
他需要新鲜空气
McCoy, what are you doing up there? Drop that thing and get down here quick.
麦考，你在上面干什么，丢了那东西快下来
What do you want me to do? Jump?
你让我怎么下来？跳下来？
I don't care what you do. Make it fast.
这我不管，快点！
- Fast enough?
够快了吧？
- Where are the hostages?
人质在哪儿？
They must be delayed in the shelter. Bobby's with them.
他们可能遇到了麻烦，波比带着他们
[man] This'll hold you till we get you to a hospital.
这个足够你坚持到医院了
Not a local hospital, I hope.
但愿不是到当地的医院
Hey, am I gonna lose the leg?
你说，这条腿能保住吗？
Don't worry. You'll be jogging by next week. Let's go.
不用担心，下个星期你就能满地跑了
Let me carry him. You've enough to do.
让我来照顾他吧，你已经够累的了
Thank you. Gentlemen, follow me quickly.
谢谢快跟我来
Better hurry. I think there's heavy reinforcements are on the way.
得赶快离开，我想他们的重装备增援部队已经在路上了
- How do you know?
你怎么知道？
- Something I heard on the radio.
我在他们的无线电通话中听到的
I didn't know you spoke Arabic.
我不知道你还会说阿拉伯语
Ifwe don't get outta here, we'll all be speaking it.
要是不走的话，这辈子只能讲阿拉伯语了
Bobby! Come on.
波比，快走！
- Watch his leg.
注意他的腿
- Let's just go. Come on.
快走，来
[Nick] Come on, keep it moving. Keep it moving. Let's go.
来，快点走，快点走
Come on, men, we gotta go. Let's go, come on.
快，我们去那儿，我们走，快上车
[man] Hit it. Move it, move it. Go!
弄开它，快，快
Goddamn place is empty.
见鬼，这里是空的
Looks like they've been here.
看，他们来过这儿
- Come on. Let's go.
快点，快！
- Delta One.
德尔塔一号
- Delta Two here.
这里是德尔塔二号
Colonel, by the looks of it, their headquarters is empty.
上校，搜寻完毕，他们的总部没人
The cells are, I repeat, the cells are empty.
囚室也是空的，我重复一遍，囚室也是空的
Looks like they've taken our people away.
看来他们把人质转移了
Then find 'em, damn it.
快去把他们找回来，见鬼
Any suggestions, Delta One?
你有什么办法吗？德尔塔一号
Beggin' the Colonel's pardon, but Beirut's a goddamn big city.
你饶了我们吧，贝鲁特是个大城市
There's over two million people here.
这儿的人口超过200万
You know what to do, Pete.
你知道该怎么做，彼德
Find one that speaks English and work on him.
快去找个会说英语的俘虏
Come on, boys! You gotta move fast!
快！你不能快点吗？
Gotta find one who'll talk.
去找个俘虏
- Where'd you find 'em all?
在哪儿找到他们的？
- Hiding in the bedrooms upstairs.
他们躲在在楼上的卧室里
Yeah?
是吗？
Now, who is your commanding officer?
说，谁是你们的头？
Speak or you're dead.
不说就打死你们
- Officer. You? You? Officer?
是你？是你？
Come here. Get up.
你给我过来，起来
Open your mouth. Open your mouth. Mouth.
把嘴张开，把嘴张开，嘴！
Ah, ah!
啊，啊！
- Ah, ah, ah.
啊，啊，啊
- Nod if you wanna live.
想死还是想活？
Do you wanna live? Live?
你想活吗？想活？
- Where did they take the Americans?
他们把人质带到哪儿去了？
- Ah, ah...
啊，啊…
Where did they take the Americans?
他们把人质带到哪儿去了？
我听见你了，贾米尔
我们刚从霍梅尼处得到消息
他同意吗？
阿亚图拉欢迎你和人质
上帝保佑，贾米尔
马哈福兹将军会见你
他会带你穿过叙利亚去见阿亚图拉
First and ten, Delta One. They're on their way to Teheran.
德尔塔一号，他们去德黑兰了
They should be somewhere on the Damascus road right now.
现在正在通往大马士革的路上
- Go after them.
去截住他们
- Yes, sir. I'll see you when I see you.
是，长官，到时候见
OK, let's move!
出发！
Damn. It's gonna be light soon.
很快就要结束了
Take off, Nick. I'll delay the reinforcements.
你们先走，上校，我去截住援军
OK. Then you join Pete.
好，完成后去和彼德会合
I'll see you at the airport.
机场见
I won't be able to wait for you.
我没时间等你
- Then don't wait.
不用等我
- I won't.
我才不等呢
OK, Bobby, you stick with the major.
波比，你跟着少校
Then take my vehicle and meet us back at the orchard.
开我的车去，我们在果园那边等着你们
- Will do.
知道了
- All right, let's go. Come on.
那好，快去吧
Delta Two, this is Delta One. Over.
德尔塔二号，这里是德尔塔一号
- What's the plan, boss?
怎么干，头？
- A surprise party.
一场惊喜大派对！
- Just like the old days.
就像以前那样
- You got it.
对
Delta Two, Delta One. Come in.
德尔塔二号，这里是德尔塔一号，请回话
I'm gonna prepare the upper floors.
我到楼上去准备一下
Yeah, I'm here, Major.
我听见了，少校
[Scott] How's it goin', kid?
情况怎么样？
Well, those bastards snaked us, boss. [spits] I'm gonna go get 'em.
那些该死的已经溜了，现在去追他们
[Scott] Watch your ass, Butch, OK?
巴奇，你要小心点
Yeah, I'll see you when I see you, boss.
知道了，机场见吧
- Bobby.
波比
- Yo.
在
- It's showtime.
是时候了，
- Let's rock 'n' roll.
动手吧
没有我的命令不许动
感觉美国人还在这儿
我担心我们来不及了
也许是个陷阱，好像有埋伏
我不这么想
司令...我觉得你想错了
全能的主啊
向学校攻击
黎巴嫩
大马士革公路7月23日星期二上午5:50
为什么停车
不是我，是他
出什么事了，为什么停车？
快走！
快看他...快看他
你们就因为一个骑摩托的人停下来？快走！
快走！
快撤！撤回贝鲁特！
Goddamn. That's Scott down there. All right, let's rock 'n' roll, partner.
天哪，原来是麦考，太好了，我们赶快行动吧
OK, let's move! Let's go!
快点，快跟上！
Let's take 'em.
让我们干掉他们
They're our guys. They're Americans. They're Delta Force.
是我们的人，美国人，他们是三角洲部队
Need a hand?
要帮忙吗？
Grab the wheel!
你来开车
快逃！
Cover us.
掩护我们
Pete. Pete.
彼德，彼德
Gimme that blanket.
把毛毯给我
Pete.
彼德
- Take off his clothes.
脱掉衣服
- Pete.
彼德
Jesus... Pete.
天哪…彼德
- You know the way to the airport?
你认识去机场的路吗？
- Yes, Major.
认识
Get the hostages out of the truck and put them in our vehicles.
叫人质上我们的车，赶快带他们走
The Colonel will be waiting for you at an orange grove behind the airport.
上校在飞机场后面的果园等你们
- Don't stop for anything, understand?
不要随便停车，明白吗？
- Yes, sir.
明白
I'll take your bike.
我用一下你的车
- What about you, Major?
少校，你干什么去？
- I've got some business to finish.
我还有点事没有办完
Tell the colonel not to wait for me.
告诉上校，不用等我
I need more bandages. There's too much blood.
再给点绑带，那儿血流得很多
有人吗？
Going somewhere?
想去哪儿？
Pete.
彼德
Hey, doc. Get on Pete here.
医生，去彼德那儿看看
Keep it quiet.
大家安静点
Mike, bring my bag. And the oxygen, too.
麦克，把我的药箱和氧气瓶拿来
- Looks like they're expecting us.
看起来他们正严阵以待
- Yes, sir.
是啊
We're gonna have to find another way.
看来要另找途径了
Maybe we could cut through the back fence.
我们也许能从棉花地穿过去
Yeah.
好的
Looks quiet.
没动静
How many guards around the plane do you figure?
你估计飞机上有多少守卫
I'd say between 12 and 16.
我想有12到16个
Six of our men.
派6个人去
- Oh!
哦！
- Ah!
啊！
Ah! [yells]
出什么事？过来
- [Nick] Do you speak English?
会说英语吗？
- [man] Yeah.
会
[Nick] You wanna live, talk fast. Who's in charge here?
想活命就说实话，谁在指挥？
Jaaffer. He is in the plane.
是贾法尔，他在飞机上
- How many men does he have?
机上有多少人？
- Nobody.
就他一个
- Come on.
快说！
- I swear by Allah he is alone.
我向阿拉起誓，就他一个
What about the hostages?
人质呢？
There are only three, sleeping in the cockpit.
有三个，都睡在驾驶舱里
Do you have a password?
有口令吗？
If you wanna live, then use it.
想活命的话就快说出来
贾法尔·伊本·卡里尔，“从山上来”
- Maybe he is asleep.
也许他睡着了
- Wake him up.
叫醒他
Jaaffer Iben Khalil.
贾法尔·伊本·卡里尔
“从山上来”，快回答
什么
- Good morning.
早上好！
- Morning.
Good morning, gentlemen. Colonel Alexander. Delta Force.
早上好，先生们，我是特种部队的亚历山大上校
- It's about time.
你们来得太好了！
- Got enough fuel?
燃料够吗？
- For what?
去哪儿？
- To fly to Israel.
飞往以色列
You bet.
足够了
Need anything else to get this thing off the ground?
还需要点什么才能顺利起飞
Yeah. A clear runway.
需要畅通的跑道
OK. All right, Jim, bring 'em in. Bring 'em in.
好了，吉姆，带人质上飞机
- Come on, gang.
行了，伙计们，
- Let's get our butt moving.
准备起飞
Let's go!
快上！
Sit down in the rear and buckle up. We gotta get out of here fast.
快到后面去坐好，我们必须尽快离开这儿
Come on, move, move, move.
快！快！快！
[man] Everybody find a seat fast!
大家赶快找好座位
Put him in first class.
把他放在头等舱
Keep moving. If they're not wounded, move to the back of the plane.
没有受伤的都到后面去，快点
Put him over there. Come on.
把他放那上面，快
Get 'em down there. Keep going.
带他们到那儿去，抓紧
Come on. Are you all right? Get in the back.
快点，你不明白吗？到后面去
You, too.
你也去
[man] Come on. Double time. Let's go! Come on!
快，这是第二次了，上去。快！
Pull it!
拉住
Where is that McCoy?
麦考在哪儿？
- Intercom check.
对讲机检查了吗？
- Check.
检查完毕
All right, Captain. Everybody's onboard.
好，机长，所有的人都登机了
Let's wind this son of a bitch up and get outta here
让我们赶快离开这个鬼地方
before the whole of Beirut shows up.
要不然贝鲁特又会出什么乱子
You got it.
明白
OK. High-pressure start... number two.
好，高压启动，起飞
萨米尔,快！
拦住飞机
Come on. Let's go. Close that hatch.
快，我们起飞，关上舱门
- Colonel, what about Major McCoy?
上校，麦考怎么办？
- We can't wait. He's always late.
我们不等他，他老是迟到
I gotta get these people outta here. Come on, move!
我要对所有的人负责，快走！
OK, gang, let's go.
行了，走了！
Flight 282. Flight 282, what are you doing?
282班机，282班机，你们在干吗？
You have no authorization to move.
你们没被允许起飞
Stay where you are.
请呆在原地
Beirut, this is American Travelways flight 282.
贝鲁特，这是美航282
I wanna thank you for an interesting stay in Beirut.
非常感谢在我们逗留贝鲁特期间你们给予的特殊款待
Hope you all have a nice day.
祝你快乐
ATW 282, out.
282号向你们告别
他们疯了...他们疯了
他们控制不住自己了
Hell, they're shooting at us.
见鬼，他们在向我们射击
Colonel, it's the major!
上校，是麦考！
Well, come on. Get a rope down to him.
快，快放条绳子下去
Ready? OK.
大家抓紧
That's it. We got you. Don't worry. Pull, pull!
抓住绳子，用力拉，拉！
Steward, close the door.
斯图沃德，把舱门关上
Let's go. Goose this bird and let's get outta here.
现在最好让我们马上升空
I don't know that we have enough room.
我不知道距离够不够
We won't have a second chance. Give it all you got.
我们没有第二次机会，你尽力吧
- All right. Here we go.
好，升空
How's Pete?
彼德怎样了？
He's up front.
他在前面
Doc set up a hospital in the first-class section.
医生在头等舱陪着他
Hey, guys, Budweisers. Let's pass 'em over.
嘿，百威啤酒，大家传一下
Pass 'em over. There's lots more where these came from.
给大家传一下，这次带了好多啤酒
How is he, doc?
医生，他怎么样？
Boss.
头
Hey, kid.
嘿，小子
Did we get 'em all out?
你把他们都干掉了吗？
Yeah, we got 'em all.
是的，我把他们全干掉了
Are we goin' home now?
我们现在准备回家吗？
We're goin' home.
我们在回家路上
Well, I'll see you there, Scott.
好，我与你在那里再见
See you when I see you.
下辈子再见
Doc...
医生…
America, America
亚美利加，亚美利加
God shed his grace on thee
上帝赐福与您
And crown thy good with brotherhood
以兄弟之爱为称的善行加冕
From sea to shining sea
从大海到闪亮的波涛
Greater love no man hath than he gives up his life for a friend.
最大的爱，莫过于他为朋友献出自己的生命
Heavenly Father, we humbly ask you
天父，我们谦卑的请求你
that you cherish this most loving soul
用你那永恒的手
in the palm of your hand for all eternity.
怀抱这最有爱的灵魂
In the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Ghost.
以天父天子之名，哈利路亚
Amen.
阿门
以色列
本·古里安机场7月23日星期二上午8:00
- Oh, my God.
哦，天哪
I'll be OK. You all right? You safe?
我没事，你还好吗？你安全了
How are you?
你好吗？
Don't give up on this airplane.
不要再上这架飞机了